Gaurav Upadhyay

Seattle, WA | (206) 535-4319 | gauravupadhyay1100@gmail.com | portfolio | linkedin | github

Summary____

I'm currently seeking a full-time role in full-stack or back-end development. I graduated from Syracuse University with a M.S. in Cyber Security and Computer Science, with 2.5+ years of professional experience in backend engineering and mobile development.

Experience

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER | AWS | SEATTLE, WA | JULY 2022 - PRESENT

- · Architected and developed backend solutions for the **AWS Console Mobile App**, creating new APIs and enhancing app functionality.
- Led the development of a new and improved **Services page**, increasing services displayed from 23 to 35, which boosted iOS traffic by **94**% and Android traffic by **83**%.
- Launched the **Universal Linking** feature for seamless navigation to AWS resources within the app, resulting in an **88%** increase in iOS traffic and a **94%** increase on Android.
- Utilized Java, Kotlin, and Swift with Android Studio and Xcode for development and testing, along with Ruby for Cucumber testing for various APIs and scenarios

COMPUTER SYSTEM ANALYST | STANLEY LAW | SYRACUSE, NY | JUNE 2021 - JUNE 2022

- · Worked with senior partners for **IT security planning** of the firm and implementation of scheduled sustainment tasks, **SSL certificate renewals**, software updates and other security updates to ensure data privacy.
- Successfully **troubleshoot** and **resolved operational** and **technical issues** by accessing business impact, identifying the root cause, to facilitate timely remediation of systems and failures
- Published weekly reports for the **Critical deadlines** of the firm to ensure that the requirements or necessary steps are being taken before the deadline has been approached.

STUDENT SUPERVISOR | SYRACUSE UNIVERSITY | SYRACUSE, NY | JAN 2021 - MAY 2021

- Supervised monitored performance and prompted corrective feedback to the team of 20 on the compliance of standards.
- · Looked after the **administrative** and **payroll** functionalities and was responsible for the daily operations of the dining facility.

Education

M.S, CYBERSECURITY AND COMPUTER SCIENCE | SYRACUSE UNIVERSITY, NY | JAN 2021 - MAY 2022 B.E, COMPUTER SCIENCE | SAVITRIBAI PHULE PUNE UNIVERSITY, INDIA | AUG 2016 - JUNE 2020

Technical Skills

Profession Skills: Full-Stack Development, Backend Development, UI Design, REST API Development Programming: Java, Kotlin, Python, C++

Web Development: JavaScript, Typescript, MongoDB, Node.js, jQuery, HTML/CSS, MySQL

Tools: Linux, Android, Git, Mac